and it is very interesting and there is a celebration on
и очень интересно и там торжество на
Easter if well, we
Пасху происходит если вот ну у нас у
Christians have a holiday, the most important thing is
крестиан у нас праздник самое главное ну
Sunday itself, yes, but for them the celebration
само воскресенье да то у них торжество
begins on Friday, that is, on Good
начинается в пятницу то есть в страстную
Friday, and it is at this time that everyone goes out
пятницу и именно в это время все выходят
into the street, and dressed in their best clothes and happy,
на улицу а парадно одетые и счастливые
that is, they carry the crucified Christ, and
то есть несут распято распятого Хреста а
everyone rejoices and they carry the crucified Christ,
все радуются и э несут Христа распятого
people in balaclavas, very
люди в в балаклавах таких притом очень
expensive ones, that is, costumes there cost 4,000
дорогих то есть костюмы там по 4.000
euros, yeah, very, very expensive, but in
евро угу вот очень очень дорогие а но на
fact, you know, the costumes of the
самом деле это вот знаете костюмы куклыс
Klan dolls are the costumes of the killers,
клановцев это костюмы убийц
hello,
здравствуйте
hello, where are you from in
здравствуйте вы откуда
Russia,
с России
and where exactly
а откуда именно
from the Volga region, well, the Volga
с Поволжья
region is a big
ну Поволжье большое
city, if the Vorotynets himself
такой город если воротынец сам
says anything, what kind of Vorotynets, Vorotynets, yes, I
что-нибудь говорит какой воротынец
know, you know why it is called Vorotynets,
знаю знаете почему он называется
why it is called Vorotynets, I don’t
что почему он вратынец называется не
know, no, because there was a princely customs office there,
знаю нет потому что там таможня была
it was on the border,
княжеская это было он был на пограниче
it was like a gate to the Muscovite
это было как бы врата в московское
state, and then Tartary was
государство а дальше уже Тартария была
probably
возможно
you are talking about history i am a historian yes i am a
вы по истории общаетесь я историк да я
historian so i have 18 years of practice
историк поэтому у меня 18 лет практики
in 2 years i will be twenty my
через 2 года будет двадцаточка
dissertation was written by a candidate of sciences I am writing a
диссертацию писал кандидат наук пишу
doctoral dissertation now yeah yeah I see do you
докторскую сейчас
know the problem of the settlement of
угу ясно а знаете проблема расселения
Jews in Europe how did they
евреев по Европе каким образом они в
end up in Spain
Испании оказались
uh Spanish Jews were called Marranos there there were
ээ испанские евреи там назывались мараны
several
там там было несколько
branches of migration some were through
веток миграции некоторые были через
Africa some came through the Roman
Африку зашли некоторые через Римскую
Empire
империю
and in what years
а в каких годах
uh different branches of migration I don't I am not
ээ разные ветки были миграции я не я не
strong in the history of the Jewish people in
силён в истории еврейского народа в
Europe yes because well this is not my
Европе да потому что ну это не есть мой
profile yes but there were very different
профиль да но там были очень разные
branches of migration because it was in the
ветки миграции потому что было в
ancient Roman Empire and the persecution of
древнерийской империи и гонения
Jews then there were in the late
еврейские потом были в позднюю уже в
Catholic era also there uh some
католическую эпоху тоже там ээ некоторые
such unrest in some countries and there
такие волнения в некоторых странах и
were migrations so there were several waves well
были миграции поэтому тут несколько волн
at least thank you
было ну по крайне мере спасибо
interesting what years only interesting how
интересный что года только интересны как
in what years just I was in a
в каких годах просто я бывал в таком
city like Seville it is a very beautiful city and
городе как Севили очень красивый город и
there the city center the city center is called the
там центр города центр города называется
Jewish Quarter
Иудейский квартал
that's very interesting and they say that the
вот очень интересно а говорят что это
whole culture there is Arab well here you are tormented by
вся культура там арабская ну вот терзате
vague doubts I think that  not exactly
смутные сомнения думаю что не совсем она
Arabic but somehow somehow
арабская а вот как-то каким-то образом
connected with the Jews who lived there
связано с евреями которые там проживали
and it is very interesting and there is a celebration on
и очень интересно и там торжество на
Easter if here among us
Пасху происходит если вот у нас у
peasants we have a holiday the most important thing well
крестьян у нас праздник самое главное ну
Sunday itself yes then their celebration
самого воскресенье да то у них торжество
begins on Friday that is on Good
начинается в пятницу то есть в страстную
Friday and it is at this time that everyone goes out
пятницу и именно в это время все выходят
into the street and dressed up and happy
на улицу а парадно одетые и счастливые
that is they carry a crucified cross and
то есть несут распято распятого креста а
everyone rejoices well
все радуются
look the idea is that local
ну это смотрите идея в том что локальные
features in each city were their own
особенности в каждом городе были свои
because before there was no television there
потому что раньше не было телевидения не
was no radio and local traditions they lived
было радио и локальные традиции они жили
in those communities that uh where people
в тех сообществах которые ээ где люди
could get to yes for example now you
могли доехать да например сейчас вы
could visit Seville and before you were from
могли побывать в Севильи а раньше вы из
uh the Volga region and further than the Volga region most
ээ Поволжья а дальше Поволжья скорее
likely did not get well
всего не доезжали
I think that merchants went there too
ну я думаю что купцы ходили туда тоже
this was a rarity it was a small
это это редкость была это небольшое
number of people yes there is well well
количество людей да ест ну ну
naturally naturally but nevertheless it is
естественно естественно но тем не менее
interesting itself I will return if we
интересно само вот я вернусь если уж
have already talked about Seville that here is the most
разговорили о Севилье что вот самая
Holy Friday yes the hardest well the
пятница как страстная да самая тяжё ну
most terrible day is the hardest
самый страшной день такой самый тяжёлый
in the studio and they have joy there and uh they
по по студии а у них там радость и ээ
carry Christ here for the fifth time people in ba
несут Христа вот раз пятого люди в ба в
in balaclavas such and very expensive
в балаклавах таких притом очень дорогих
that is the costumes there are 4,000 euros yeah that's
то есть костюмы там по 4.000 евро угу
very very expensive but in
вот очень очень дорогие а но на самом
fact these are you know the costumes of the Ku Klux
деле это вот знаете костюмы куклус
Klan these are the costumes of killers actually that is so that
клановцев это костюмы убийц вообще-то
you are not seen yes these are the
вот то есть чтобы тебя не видели да это
costumes of killers no no not quite so no the
костюмы убийц нет не не совсем так нет
clan is an American tradition it
клан - это традиция американская она не
has nothing to do with Spain and with
имеет никакого отношения к Испании и к
Seville absolutely nothing well okay
Севильи абсолютно никакого ну хорошо вот
look I'll explain I'll explain I'll explain
смотрите я объясню я объясню я объясню
where this tradition comes from the fact that in
откуда эта традиция дело в том что в
Zoroastrianism in Zoroastrianism and in other in
зороастризме в зороастризме и в другие в
some currents of Christianity
некоторых течениях христианства потому
because Zoroastrianism gave a very big
что зороастризм дал очень большое
influence on early Christianity and on
влияние на раннее христианство и на
early Christian communities there was a cult uh
раннехристианские общины был культ ээ
such that it was necessary to hide from evil
такой что нужно было спрятаться от злых
forces because if evil forces see
сил потому что если злые силы увидят
your face they can then gain
твоё лицо они могут тогда получить
power over you yes that's where it was they
власть над тобой да оттуда и было
came up with this fairy tale killers
это вот придумали эту сказку убийцы
who  they
которые
performed their function and then such a
выполняли свою функцию и потом такая
fairy tale was born to justify and also
сказка родилась чтобы оправдать и также
uh in Seville no one will say why they
ээ в Севильи никто не скажет зачем они
they explain this to show suffering
они объясняются это показать страдания
what suffering when you have a suit that
какие страдания когда ты у тебя костюм
hides your face not only your face question
скрывающий лицо не только лицо вопрос
question look in the Russian Empire there
вопрос смотрите в Российской империи там
and in general in Sonic at masquerades at
и вообще в соникове на маскарадах на
balls there were masquerades people hid their faces
балах были маскарады люди скрывали лицо
why yes yes exactly exactly so and they
почему да да точно точно так а они
were killers that and at a masquerade it is
убийцы были та а на маскараде это
firstly the masquerade itself it and to raise the
во-первых сам маскарад он а поднять
mood and a mask at a masquerade is uh
настроение а а маска на маскараде - это
and how to say a form of surprise to surprise you
э а как сказать форма удивления удивить
understand and each mask is different yes well uh
понимаете и каждая маска разная да ну э
there is a certain suit and here it is
там определённый костюм а здесь она
unified and special I
унифицированная и специальная ещё раз
say again specifically to instill fear if a
говорю специально навести страх если
person is not knowledgeable if for example to
человек не сведущий вот если например
our child even from Ukraine or from
нашему ребёнку да хоть с Украины хоть с
Russia show this procession then he will be
России показать эту процессию то он
horrified he will become scared you understand that
ужаснётся ему станет страшно понимаете
is this procession of
то есть это процессия ещё раз
executioners
говорю палачей
I will say more than that you
я больше того скажу вот вы свинину
eat pork yes
едите да
yes if you show people from Israel or Arabs
да если людям из Израиля или арабам
how you eat pork they will also
показать как вы едите свинину им тоже
become scared
станет страшно
well you understand what is exactly about here  not about that
ну вы поняли о чём здесь как раз не о
but namely visual contacts yes
том что а именно визуальные контакты да
I understand different cultures yes let's see
я понимаю разную культуру да посмотрим
for example if let's say in the Russian tradition
например если скажем в русской традиции
so in the Russian tradition you need to jump
так вот в русской традиции нужно прыгать
into this cold hole in short in the ice hole yes
в холодную эту дырку короче в прорубе да
if you show it to people from Seville they will also
если показать людям из Севильи они тоже
think that it is scary that these are
подумают что это страшно что это
some crazy people really well once
какие-то сумасшедшие правда
again I'm not talking about that madness
ну ещё раз говорю не о том сумасшествии
says they will think that it is strange and
говорит они подумают что это странно и
they
им
may even be scared to
возможно это будет даже страшно там
jump there but horror real horror it will not
прыгнуть но ужас ужас реальный это не
cause and I specifically took a child a
вызовет а я специально примел ребёнок
child and pictures it is good if to tell a child yes
ребёнок и карти хорошо если ребёнку да
from some countries that Russians
из некоторых стран сказать что русские
worship relics of corpses yes for example
поклоняются мощам трупам да например
saints yes bones of saints the dried hand
святых да костям святых высохшая рука
there of John the Baptist yes will this cause
там Иоанна Крестителя да это вызовет ли
fear or disgust in a person well it
это страх или отвращение у человека ну
is possible to disgust of course yes of course yes and
можно отвращать конечно да конечно да а
why do Russians worship relics of corpses
почему русские поклоняются мощам трупам
well I don't know the background of this well
ну я предыстории этого не знаю ну такая
such a culture exists
такая культура существует
but it is some kind of that is to drag not
но это ж какой-то то есть таскать не
bury a corpse but to drag its parts
похоронить труп а таскать его части
pray to them more  once I say it is
молиться им ещё раз говорю это там
considered there the incorruptible part of a holy
считается нетленная часть святого
person yes touching him well in
человека да прикосновение к нему ну на
fact if we went to that let's
самом деле если уж на то пошёл пошли
talk
разговор по
about well the remains of a person of such a
поводу ну останков человека такого
nature aa which do not decompose in
характера аа которые не разлагаются в
principle the human body is the clothes of a
принципе тело человека - это одежда
person who in the end when he
человека который в конце концов когда он
dies not just interesting where it is from this is
уходит не просто интересно откуда вот
such a wild custom yes dead saints
это такой дикий обычай да умерших святых
are dragged apart and kept well in
растаскивать на части и держать их ну на
fact the largest what is it
самом деле самый большой как это
called not an acropolis but an acropolis
называется не акрополь а акрополь
or whatever it is called it is located
или как как это называется это находится
mausoleums you wanted no not mausoleums but
мавзаолей вы хотели нет не мавзаолей а
namely the relics of saints this is the Kivopechersk
именно мощи святых это кивопечерская
lava cave yes also this is there is
лава пещера да также это есть вот есть
such a city yes I'm saying if you show
такой город да я же говорю если показать
if you show the children from Seville these
если показать детям из Севильи вот этих
corpses
трупаков
they will be somehow surprised let's say this
они же будут как-то удивлены скажем это
again I say this a slightly different word is
ещё раз говорю это немножко другое слово
used
используется
corpses
трупляется
this is an inanimate non-living body this non-
это неживое не живое тело на это не
living body is a corpse a corpse there are already
живое тело это труп труп там кости уже
bones
кости
I'm not going to say again I don't
я не собираюсь ещё раз говорю у меня
have an answer to your questions in this
нету ответа на ваши вопросы в этом
regard I don't know history just if
отношении я не знаю история просто если
you look at this let's Seville which in
посмо вот это давайте севили который в
balaclava yes show that they are holding a
балаклаве да показать что тут держат
dried-up corpse here he will say these are some kind of
труп высохший он скажет это какие-то
murderers the point is not in this again I say
убийцы смысл-то не в этом ещё раз говорю
so and think Maybe and think maybe and
так и подума Может и подумаеть может и
think I say again just a story
подумать я ещё раз говорю просто рассказ
about what the costume symbolizes that is
о том а о чём символизирует костюм вот э
not true this is a costume I say again of
это неправда это костюм ещё раз говорю
executioners who hid their time and
палачей которые скрывали своё время и
terrified someone yes let's say that
наводили ужас на кого-то да так скажем
is doll costumes from the clan just like
то есть костюмы куклы с клана так же как
those used in America are
которые использовались в Америке- это
costumes that should terrify
костюмы которые должны наводить ужас
then in America it was on blacks you
тогда в Америке это на чернокожих
understand and they imagined themselves took a
понимаете и они возомнили себя взяли
certain right and executed there they terrified
определённое право и казнили там
horror that's the point and how do
наводили ужас ужас вот в этом смысл а а
you by the way how do you by the way evaluate
как вы кстати как вы кстати оцениваете
historically because I am no longer based
вот исторически потому что я больше не
on the period of Europe but on the period of the
по периоду Европы а по периоду
Russian Empire yes uh Jewish
Российской империи да ээ еврейские
pogroms in the Russian Empire well
погромы в Российской империи
about the pogroms I only heard that
ну про погромы я слышал только которые
were in Kyiv and in Moscow there were I don't know in the
были в Киеве а в Москве были я не знаю в
sense in Moscow Jews did not live look
смысле в в Москве евреи не жили смотрите
in Chisinau there was in Odessa and so yes yes
в Кишинёве был по в Одессе и так да да
below perhaps I say again I am not an
ниже возможно ещё раз говорю я не
expert in this  but well Russians look the
специалист в этом но ну русские смотри
organization of the Archangel
организация архистратига архангела
Michael was yes Russian black-sounding
Михаила была да Русская черносоная
organization yes again
организация да ещё раз
yate but this is the question itself in general why
яте но это сам вопрос вообще почему
was there persecution of Jews that's
гонение на евреев бывало вот заче
why everywhere this is not only in the
почему везде это не только в конце
end the most extreme is genocide which was
концов самый максимальный это геноцид
carried out
которыйло который произвёл
there by Hitler yes or no no this is already the middle of the
там Гитлер да или не не это уже середина
20th century yes these were the root causes
XX века да это ведь первопричинами были
here in the Russian Empire there was a Pale of
вот в Российской империи была черта
Saddle Jews were forbidden to settle
седлости евреям запрещали селиться
Jews the Pale of Saddle this is exactly so
евреям черта седлости это как раз точно
it was Catherine who established the Pale of
так это Екатерина установила черту о
Saddle Jews yes they
седлости евреев да
forbade
запрещали
Jews yes yes I understand I have an answer
евреям да да я понял у меня есть ответ
to this specific yes that is to say at
на этот определённый да то есть в
some time Jews were the ruling
какое-то время евреи были правящим
class and not only in Russia yes including
классом и не только в России да в том
in the same Spain and including
числе и в той же Испании и в том числе и
in
в
Can you clarify when in Russia when in
Можете уточнить когда в России когда в
Russia Jews were the ruling class
России евреи были правящим классом
well in the Copenhagen Museum there is an image of
ну в музее Копенгагена есть изображение
Ivan IV Ivan the Terrible and in the form of an icon
Ивана IV Иована Грозного а в виде иконы
yes it is an icon although  is it considered an icon
да это икона хотя это считается ли икона
that it is a transitional class this image
что это переходный класс это изображение
there it is well at least as they say
там оно ну по крайней мере как говорится
there it is nominated yes that this is an
там она так номинуется да что это
image of Ivan the Terrible if you look at it
изображение Ивана Грозного если вы на её
then there is absolutely
посмотрите то славянино там совершенно
no smell of Slavic there it is not a Slav so he is a Turk he
не пахнет это не славянин так он тюрок
was a Turk and not a Turk
он тюрок был и не тюрок
look at him that is there is a Jew Well
посмотрите на него то есть там евре Ну
you as a historian probably know
вы как как историк наверное может знаете
more I don't know I'm just saying that
больше я я не знаю я просто говорю то
I know I looked at it and it
что вот я знаю я посмотрел на неё и он
looks more like a Roman well more like a
больше ну на рменина похож на ну больше
Jew and moreover moreover
на еврея и более того более того
John is a Jewish name that is the first
Иоанн - это еврейское имя то есть первое
first burial in the Archangel
первое захоронение в Архангельском
Cathedral of the Moscow Kremlin yes Ivan
соборе Московского Кремля да Ивана
Kolita yes John that is it is Jewish yet it is not a Slavic
Колиты да иоан то есть это еврейское ещё
name yes it is not
это не славянское имя да она не
Slavic here are the Slavic princes like
славянское вот славянские князья как
Vladimir Yaroslav Svyatoslav exactly exactly so exactly so exactly
были владимир Ярослав Святослав точно
so
точно так точно так точно так
accordingly John the First John the Second
соответственно Иоанн первый Иоанн второй
John I yes or there and Vasily in the
Иоанн Iй да или там и Василий в конце
end they had Jewish blood yes
концов они имели еврейскую кровь да
you understand if the name that is
понимаете если наименование то то есть
they were Jews and what in history  erased
они были евреями а что в истории стёрто
erased I don't know but nevertheless it
затёрто не знаю но тем не менее это так
was so that is the country which Ukrainians
было то есть та страна которую украинцы
now call Muscovy yes it was
сейчас называют Московией да это вот
headed by Jews but at that time I
возглавлялось евреями но в это время ещё
say again Jews visited were in
раз говорю евреи посети находились у
power not only in Russia but also in Europe
власти не только в России а и в Европе
also yes that is at least in the north of
также да то есть по крайне мере север
Italy uh the center of culture of Spain Seville
Италии э центр культуры Испании Севилья
Gnada these were the centers of Judaism you
Гнада это были центры еврейства
understand and they are there and in fact
понимаете и они там и на самом деле
Jews and now the
евреи и сейчас находятся у власти самые
richest people in the world are in power I mask I don't know
богатые люди мира я маска не знаю он
if he has Jewish
имеет ли он еврейскую
blood but all the rich people in the world they are
кровь а так все богатые люди мира они
Jews
евреи
well your richest man now in
ну ваш самый богатый человек сейчас на
Ukraine is also Jews who well let's not no who who is the most
Украине тоже евреи кто ну не будем не не
I just don't know who is the
кто кто самый я просто не знаю кто самый
richest among us well listen let's not zav
богатый у нас ну слушайте не будем зав
Even name us well it's not scary to name us
Даже назовите ну нас не страшно назвать
I can And come on democracy I'll talk
я я могу А дава же демократия я поговорю
about yours it's like now he is not the
про вашего это как сейчас он не
president anymore well and about Zelensky I say
президент уже ну а про Зеленского говорю
Zelensky is the richest well probably
зеленский самый богатый ну наверное
not very poor but can you tell me
не не очень бедный а можете сказать
what his just interesting interesting well
какие его просто интересно интересно ну
let's go I know I know Jewish
давайте вот я знаю я знаю еврейских
oligarchs
олигархов
for example there and  Zelensky what
например там а Зеленский какие у него
assets does he have well you said that he is the
активы ну так вы же сказали что он самый
richest I assumed otherwise tell me I assume
богатый я предположил а то скажите я
again I say I am not the one
предполагаю ещё раз говорю я я не не тот
who knows I am the one who heard
кто знает я который тот который слышал а
maybe yes I heard the ringing but does not know
может быть да слышал звон да не знает
where it is this is the question let's then let's
где он это вопрос давайте Давайте тогда
clarify Putin and Medvedev they Well I
уточним путин и Медведев они
don't know about the Bear they said that
Ну не знаю про Медведя наговорили что у
he has in the cow I haven't heard well Medvedev there is
него есть в корове не слышал ну Медведе
Mendel
вон Мендель
maybe I don't know I heard the Bear and he has a
возможно не знаю Медведя слышал да и у
certain behavior
него есть есть поведение определённое
corresponding
соответствующие
yes well and Putin he is clearly not Well look
да ну и Путин он явно не Ну посмотрите
he clearly does not have a Slavic appearance
он у него явно не славянская внешность у
Putin is bald also this one I have
Путина лысина также вот этот у меня
Slavs I have Slavic no and what kind of
славянс у меня славянская нет а какое у
m I have Finno-Ugric it is
меня м угрофинская
clear somewhere like Komi Permyak Komizy
ясно где-то как вот Коми Пермяк Комизы
Zyryanin is
Зырянин
very narrow well where did you see you have a very
очень узкий ну где вы видели у вас очень
narrow slit very small eyes
узкий разрезгла очень маленькие глазки
no no no this distortion is normal I have no
нене не это искажение нормально у меня
eyes no no you have very eyes you do
глаз нет нет нет у вас глаза очень у вас
not have an Asian appearance because
именно не азиатская внешность потому что
there are no epicanthus yes but very narrow eyes
нету эпикантусов да но очень узкие глаза
that is not a narrow slit but  very compressed
то есть не узкий разрез а очень сжатые
yes these are comics the idea is that comics are comedians
да это комизы идея в том что комизыряни
who
комики которые
-e developed as an ethnic group in very
-э сложились как этнос в очень
snowy areas yes uh there is a
заснеженных территориях да ээ там в чём
problem a lot of ultraviolet light
проблема очень много ультрафиолета на
falls on the snow and the snow reflects a lot so
снег падает и снег очень отбивает вот вы
when you go out into the snow you squint
когда выходите на снег вы прищуриваетесь
and it turns out that genetically that is how those who
и получается что генетически так
more well less
выживали те у которые больше ну меньше
burned their own maybe yes therefore yes well well well
обжигали свой возможно да поэтому да ну
I know my kinship by name one thread
ну вот я своё родство поимённо по одной
one thread of the family up to
нитке по одной нитке рода знаю до 1811
1811 that is and I know what where well I
года то есть и знаю что куда ну я
live in those places where the
проживаю в тех местах где рядом
Makarevsky Monastery is nearby thanks to
Макаревский монастырь вот благодаря
this monastery yes if you know how you are
этому монастырю да если вы знаете как вы
in Turkmenistan yes no this is the Volga Volga
в Туркменистане да нет это Волга волга
this hearing in Turkmenistan they said no no no
это слыша в Туркменистане сказали нет
I live there nearby no this is the
нет нет я проживаю там рядом нет это
Volga region this is the Nizhny Novgorod region that's how it is
Поволжь это Нижегородская область вот
there and the Makarovsky Monastery
так и там а Макаровский монастырь вот
there were archives that were more
там были архивы которые больше были
transferred to the church and the churches were
перенесены в церковь и церкви
preserved then digitized and it
сохранились потом оцифрованы и так
turned out that
получилось что
not I personally but the people who
не я лично а как бы люди которые
sorted it out they
разбирали они
found  my ancestors and a very easy
вот нашли моих предков и а очень легко
to trace because my ancestors
прослеживается потому что мои предки
named their children and so that's how that is there were
называли своих детей а вот так вот то
five generations and father son son
есть пять поколений было а отец сын сын
father yes the same name was repeated
отец да одно и то же имя повторялось
Peter Ivan Peter Ivan and what were they called well it doesn't matter
пётр Иван пётр Иван а как их называли да
so important what name
ну неважно так важно важно каким именем
and Fyodor and Mikhail that is Theodore and
а Фёдор и Михаил то есть Теодор и
Michael like these are Jewish names no
Михаэль типа это же еврейские имена нет
they were entered and moreover uh our
они вписаны были и более того э наши
names that in our area they
имена которые вот в наших местах они и
heard about such about Vyatka names of Vyatka
слышали про такой про Вятку имена Вятки
yes Vyatka yes Kira Vyatka yes well
да вятка да Кира Вятка да вот а
look how many names there are there but only
посмотрите сколько там имён там а только
male names there are several thousand it seems
мужских имён там несколько тысяч кажется
uh well in use there were still
ээ ну в использовании были всё равно
a lot there are about 200-300 names well
очень много там около 200-300 имён ну
Mikhail is this is the Archangel Michael
Михаил - это это ж архангел Михаил
Jewish yes yes yes yes yes yes yes everything is
еврейский да да да да да да да всё
correct but also this is a-e the first well the
правильно но ещё это же а-э первый ну
most interesting thing if you are a historian
самое интересное если уж вы историк я
I also started in fact the continuation of
ещё я начал на самом деле продолжение
my family thanks to these same archives
своего рода благодаря этим же архивам
by the way they are called very interestingly and these
кстати они очень интересно называются а
censuses that the wildcats drew up
переписи вот эти которые дички оформляли
they were called tales that is  tales of
они назывались сказками то есть сказки
such and such a district written by such and such a wild man yes so
такого-то уезда выполненные диьком-то
I found and the time of
таким-то да так вот я нашёл а время
birth of my village that is this and and
рождения моей деревни то есть это и а
there at the time of birth it was a census of
там во время рождения это была перепись
people who were there and I have a unique
людей кто там был и у меня уникальная
surname it is also like many Russian
фамилия она она тоже как многие русские
surnames they are by name that is well either
фамилии они а поимённо то есть ну либо
they are by the affairs which a person was engaged in
они по делам которыми человек занимался
or on behalf of an ancestor and a patronymic
или от имени предка а патронимическая
surname is called this way that is the name that is
фамилия называется это так вот то то имя
my surname and it is not there now what oh well it does not
которое моей фамилии а его сейчас нету
matter well I wonder again I
какое а ну неважно ну интересно ещё раз
will not believe it now ok do
говорю не буду поверьте его сейчас
not say your surname say
хорошо не говорите свою фамилию скажите
that name well then the surname will be known
то имя ну тогда фамилия будет известна
again I say no so the surname could have been
ещё раз говорю нет так фамилия могла и
formed differently there well tell me well the
по-другому там произвестись ну скажи ну
first three letters of the name the first three letters of the
первые три буквы имени первые три буквы
name I will not I will not you are afraid I will not I will
имени не буду не буду боитесь не буду
again I say just take my word for it
ещё раз говорю просто поверьте на слово
surname the name it existed until the 15th century
фамилия имя это существовало до XV века
as a historian this is like in support of
как историку это же вот как в поддержку
your theory which you are going on about well it's
вашей теории которая вы там едет по
just that there were other
ну просто там до XV века были другие
names for people until the 15th century and here is my family my family my family of the
имена у людей и вот мой род мой род мой
15th century names  here's the whole family, you
род XV века имена вот всей семьи вы
Evdokii No no no not once again I say no
Евдокий
luck
Нет нет нет не ещё раз говорю не уда
Netlay once again I say no well again I
Нетлай ещё раз говорю
say don't guess don't need it
не ну ещё раз говорю не угадайте не надо
well if you're not interested let's be
ну если вам не интересно давайте будьте
healthy so crucified so crucified
здоровы так распинался так распинался
subscribe to my Telegram right now axis vin
подпишись на мій Telegram прям зараз ось
and
він а
priest is even more and even more important youtube
попик це дуже і дуже важливо youtube
ban us through skarg in a shadowy ban and
заганяе нас чере скарг в тіньовий бан и
even richer  is not shown to people at all times
дуже багато не показуется людям вчасно
information about streams is not shown
не показуется інформація про стрими тому
in order for us to have a short operational link to
для того щоб ми мали оперативный зв'язок
subscribe right away and a pop there in the
підпишиться прям зараз а попик там в
telegram okmdeo is also useful and relevant
телеграмі окмдео ще теж цікава и корисна
information and we are responsible for you to trim the
інформація і ми повинні з вами тримати
permanent operational  zv'yazok independent
постійний оперативний зв'язок незалежно
In addition, I will show you about this YouTube,
від того чи покаже вам про цей YouTube
glory to Ukraine, subscribe
слава Україні підпишись